Senior/Principle Full Stack Engineer

Craig is a senior software engineer with seven years of experience that includes designing and building complex enterprise applications, leading development teams, and managing client and business relationships. Currently seeking an opportunity for further career growth.

Industry Experience

Cigna (2018-Present)

Software Engineer (2018-2020), Senior Software Engineer and Team Lead (2020-2021), Senior Staff Engineer (2021-Present)

- Full stack engineering role, working with Java/Kotlin/SpringBoot backend and JavaScript/TypeScript/React frontend.
- Reduced development and maintenance costs by eliminating the need for duplicate applications for different lines of business by championing a configurable extension system to allow for more flexible, multi-tenant corporate data systems.
- Boosted the speed and predictability of releases by pioneering the use of a micro-frontend architecture at the company, allowing for more narrowly focused releases of frontend applications.
- Significantly accelerated page load times, improving the user experience, by overhauling the frontend build system to reduce application size by 50%.
- Eliminated the use of an expensive and unreliable platform by developing an in-house ETL solution to handle communication between external vendors and mainframe programs.
- Grew the skillset of the broader team by running multiple sessions of an in-house React course so that traditionally backend developers could learn to contribute to the full stack.
- Reduced production bugs and workflow chaos by streamlining the software release process through documenting and standardizing the process, properly allocating resources each sprint for release tasks, and getting the business to commit to respecting the release schedule.
- Boosted the company's appeal to potential candidates by being a mentor for the corporate summer internship program, with several intern direct reports ultimately becoming full time employees of the company.
- Improved predictability to business partners by increasing sprint completion rate from ~40% to ~75% by boosting communication of capacity constraints from developer team.

PilotFish Technology (2015-2018)

Java Developer (2015-2016), Solutions Architect (2016-2018)

- Primarily backend Java role working with proprietary technology, however also included some frontend AngularJS
 development.
- Revolutionized software upgrade experience by designing an automated regression testing system to pre-emptively identify
 and report changes in behavior when moving to a newer version of the software.
- Ensured the competitiveness of a legacy medical forms company in the digital space by designing and implementing an all-in-one electronic form integration solution, complete with security protections and a customer-facing web UI.
- Boosted company's competitive advantage by designing system to allow clients to easily configure mappings of inbound legacy data feeds to modern REST API calls.
- Vastly improved the efficiency of an information provider in the insurance industry by creating an integration to automatically pull regulatory data down from multiple APIs and combine it all in their database.
- Boosted the level of communication between various labs, payers, and insurance companies in Canada by building integrations that translated various conflicting data formats.

Technical Knowledge

Languages	Frameworks/Tools	Databases	Cloud Deployment	Agile Experience
Java, JavaScript,	SpringBoot, Jersey/JAX-	PostgreSQL, MySQL,	Docker, Kubernetes,	Scrum, Kanban
HTML5/CSS3,	RS, Maven, Gradle,	SQL Server, Oracle,	CloudFoundry	
TypeScript, Kotlin, Scala,	Hibernate, React, Angular	, MongoDB		
SQL, Bash, XSLT	Vue, Svelte, Webpack,			
	Babel, NodeJS, ExpressJS	5		

Certifications

Oracle Certified Java Professional

Education

Bachelor's Degree, Ramapo College of New Jersey

Honors & Achievements

Eagle Scout, Boy Scouts of America